As you all know,
如同各位所知
when it comes to criminal cases,
針對刑事案件的處理
Japan is often considered to be behind other countries.
日本通常被認為落後於其他國家
For instance, in many countries,
例如在許多國家
the suspect has the right
一般認為嫌疑人在接受訊問時
to have an attorney present during questioning.
擁有請辯護律師陪同的權利
This is not the case in Japan.
日本則非如此
If the suspect denies the crime, their detention is extended.
若嫌疑人否認罪行，則會延長羈押
If they admit to the crime, they are granted bail.
認罪就能夠被獲准保釋
Some refer to this system as "hostage justice," and criticize it.
有些人將此制度稱為 “人質司法”並加以批判
It sounds as if the suspect is held hostage
彷彿在說我們將嫌疑人當成人質
and coerced into confessing.
強迫他們自白
Absurd!
簡直是謬論！
Also, it is most regrettable
另外，令人感到遺憾的是
that due to the unlawful actions of one prosecutor,
前陣子某位檢察官的不正當行為
trust in the prosecution has been significantly shaken.
使社會對檢方的信賴明顯動搖
This is truly disappointing.
讓人深感惋惜
My sincere apologies.
非常抱歉
Now, what will we do?
接下來，我們該怎麼做？
Here today, I want to strongly declare
今天我想在場強烈呼籲
that we should not be cowed and that we should remain confident!
我們不該畏懼退縮
We, the prosecution, obey the law,
我們檢方遵從法律
are faithful to our duties, and do what must be done.
忠誠面對職務，做該做的事情
In the first place,
說到底…
the people want guilty individuals to be punished.
對有罪者進行制裁 正是國民所希望看到的景象
We have taken their will seriously
我們誠心看重此期望
and have been seeking the truth.
持續追求真相
That is precisely how we've maintained
正因如此才能長期達成
a conviction rate of 99.9%, a rarity even globally!
全球少見 定罪率99.9%的傑出數字！
Now is the time to restore the authority of the prosecution…
現在正是我們找回檢方的威信
and show the world
將實力展示給社會大眾的時刻
that we, the prosecution, represent justice!
告訴他們我們檢方才是正義的一方！
I'm truly sorry!
真的十分抱歉！
But I won't let it end here.
但我不會讓事情就此結束
We're working on finding a way
我們正在尋找其他方法
to get a retrial as soon as--
希望能儘早再審…
Thank you.
謝謝你
I don't blame my situation on you.
我不認為是你害我陷入現在的處境
My dabbling in embezzlement
不管是侵占錢財
and my false confession…
還是針對沒做過的事認罪
They were all due to my own weakness.
全都是出於我自身的軟弱
There's no reason for you to apologize.
你完全沒必要向我低頭致歉
You're the one who sacrificed so much of your life for me and Saya.
律師，你才是犧牲最多的
It must've felt so long.
耗費了很長的時間吧？
Thanks to you…
多虧有你
I was able to see Saya again.
我才能再見到紗耶
Even yesterday, she showed me a picture.
她昨天給我看了照片
Here are Mill and Mame.
牠們分別是米魯跟小豆
Don't they look just like Cocoa?
長得跟可可很像吧？
I can't wait to show them to you.
真想快點讓爸爸也見到牠們
My hands…
我的手啊
are warm.
非常溫暖
I'm…
“我現在…
alive right now.
還活著”
I was able to feel that again.
我再次感受到這種心情
And that’s truly enough for me.
對我來說已經夠了
Mr. Shimizu!
志水先生！
You have every right…
你當然有權
to experience more happiness!
獲得更多的幸福！
I promised to secure an acquittal for you.
我曾答應你，會為你爭取無罪
Please give me
拜託你了
just a little more…
請再給我…
a little more time.
一點時間
ITOI FAMILY MURDERS CASE INVESTIGATIVE REPORT
（糸井家滅門案）
Mr. Akizumi isn't coming out today either.
明墨律師今天也窩在房內呢
It seems he isn't even going home.
他好像也沒回家
He's reviewing the case files he has already reviewed many times.
似乎在重讀已看了無數次的事件資料
By the way, did you meet the reporter acquainted with Ms. Sawahara?
話說回來，你有見到 澤原小姐認識的那位記者了嗎？
I learned a lot about the circumstances from 12 years ago,
雖然問到很多12年前的往事
but nothing decisive that would lead to a retrial.
不過沒有任何新的關鍵情報 能用來聲請再審
I shouldn't be surprised.
這也沒辦法
Finding new evidence isn't so easy.
新證據不會這麼簡單就出現
After all, it took five years to find that alibi footage.
光是找到那部不在場證明的影片 就花了五年
I'm back.
我回來了
Hey.
辛苦了
How did it go with your dad?
你爸狀況如何？
He refused to see me.
他拒絕會客
But I'll keep going
不過我會再去找他
until he agrees to testify about the footage.
直到他願意為那部影片作證
Please do.
麻煩你了
We don't have any other options at the moment.
現在我們只能靠那個方法了
What's the matter, youngster?
怎麼了？年輕人
How about we sort things out once?
我們把案情概要整理一次好嗎？
On March 5th, 2012, at Mr. Makoto Itoi's home
2012年3月5日
in Hanamigawa Ward, Chiba City, Chiba Prefecture,
在千葉縣千葉市花見川區的
his whole family was found dead.
有人發現全家人陳屍於屋內
The night before, the family had consulted a doctor,
那家人在死亡的前一晚
But they passed away before dawn.
卻在翌日天亮前死亡
After the on-site investigation,
根據現場檢驗的結果
a high concentration of thallium was detected,
因為測出了高濃度的鉈
leading to the conclusion of poisoning.
被斷定為毒殺案
According to neighbors,
依鄰居的說法
around 7:30 p.m. on the night before their deaths,
在他們死亡前一晚的7點30分左右
the Itoi family hosted a dinner party with a guest.
有客人到糸井家，他們一同用餐
The police investigated
警方認為就是這位客人將毒帶去
No hair, sebum, skin, or any other trace of the culprit was found at the scene.
毛髮、皮脂、皮膚碎屑等都沒找到
Everyone related to Mr. Itoi was thoroughly investigated,
糸井先生的交友關係被徹底翻出來
resulting in the arrest of Mr. Shimizu, who was close to the family.
而跟他們家關係密切的 志水先生就這麼被逮捕
However, on the night in question,
但實際上 當天晚上志水先生為了紗耶
According to Ms. Momose's file,
照桃瀨小姐提供的文件內容
Mr. Shimizu was seen on covert footage captured by Mr. Hiyama at 7:41 p.m.
志水先生於晚間7點41分 出現在緋山先生偷拍的影片中
On the other hand, the suspected culprit visited the Itoi home around 7:30 p.m.
另一方面，疑似嫌犯的人
Given the distance,
從距離來看
it was impossible for Mr. Shimizu to be at Mr. Itoi's home at that time.
志水先生這個時間不可能在現場
However, no one was aware of the existence of the footage at that point.
但當時沒有任何人知道這影片的存在
And only Saya knew that Mr. Shimizu had gone to a park.
而且得知志水先生 去了公園的只有紗耶
The police believed
因此警方認為是父親在哄騙五歲小孩
Additionally, evidence of his embezzlement of company funds
再加上志水先生侵占公司財產
and his conflicts with Mr. Itoi were uncovered,
以及曾經與糸井先生 產生糾紛的證據被找到
further intensifying suspicion against him.
導致他的嫌疑越來越重
I suggest you all go through this as well.
可以的話，也請你們看看這份資料
ITOI FAMILY MURDERS CASE
（糸井家滅門案）
I wonder what Ms. Momose was like.
不曉得桃瀨小姐在世時是怎麼樣的人
She was quite accomplished.
她非常優秀喔
What?
什麼？
Mr. Aoyama, you knew her too?
青山先生也認識她嗎？
She was my junior at university.
她是我讀大學時的學妹
I also aspired to become an attorney back then, you know.
我以前姑且是立志當律師
Yes.
沒錯
I tried the bar exam four times, but failed.
我挑戰司法考試，考了四次卻沒過
Despite how he may seem, he can get extremely nervous.
他雖是這副樣子，但其實容易怯場
When my wife became pregnant, I gave up and took a job as a salesperson.
妻子懷孕後我就放棄，轉當業務
But I reconnected with Mr. Akizumi five years ago.
但在五年前與明墨律師重逢
That's when I learned about Ms. Momose's passing.
我那時才聽說桃瀨小姐過世了
When I see your notebooks, Mr. Akamine,
看到赤峰先生的筆記本
they remind me of Ms. Momose.
我就會想起桃瀨小姐
She used to take notes just like you.
因為她經常像你那樣做筆記
Quite a while ago,
看似跟案件相關的東西
I handed things I thought might be related to the incident over to Mr. Akizumi.
我很久之前就幾乎都交給明墨先生了
But as I was organizing, I found some more.
但整理後又找到了一些
Thank you very much.
謝謝你
Come in.
請進
She was investigating Mr. Shimizu's case…
那孩子在醫院也一直在查案
the entire time she was in the hospital.
老是在調查志水先生的案件
She questioned the doctors about poisons and gave them a hard time.
她還詢問多位醫生 關於毒物的問題，讓他們傷透腦筋
Go ahead.
請自便
This is the diary Reiko kept until she passed away.
這是禮子寫到臨終前的日記
I couldn't…
如此貴重的東西…
I'm already grateful that Mr. Akizumi is carrying on Reiko's wish.
光是有明墨先生願意接手完成 她的遺願就讓我十分感激了
And now, with another ally like you…
如今又多了像你這樣的夥伴
she must be pleased.
我想禮子會很高興
Since she was insistent…
既然那孩子都那麼主張了
I'm sure Mr. Shimizu is innocent.
志水先生肯定是無罪的
Please help save Mr. Shimizu.
請你拯救志水先生吧
I'm back.
我回來了
Welcome back.
回來啦
Are those Ms. Momose's?
那是桃瀨小姐的？
Look at all these labels!
便利貼的數量真驚人
I thought her notes might contain clues.
我想說也許能在筆記中找到線索
Was her mother well?
她的母親過得好嗎？
Yes.
過得很好
Here.
這給你
It's Ms. Momose's diary.
是桃瀨小姐的日記
April 1st.
4月1日
I've been assigned to work under the Mr. Datehara!
我將會在伊達原先生的手下工作！
He's the prosecutor everyone in prosecution looks up to.
他是每個檢察官都嚮往的目標
I'll do my best.
我會加油
June 10th.
6月10日
I heard something troubling about Mr. Datehara.
我聽到一件跟伊達原先生有關 且讓人在意的傳聞
In the Itoi family murders case in Chiba,
聽說針對千葉的糸井家滅門案
he supposedly suppressed evidence that could have proven Shimizu's alibi.
他湮滅了證據 使志水沒有不在場證明
Here's the report on the theft case in Shinjuku.
這是新宿竊盜案的報告書
Because of that incident…
因為那起案件…
Good work.
辛苦了
Mr. Datehara was promoted to Deputy Chief Prosecutor.
伊達原先生升任為次席檢察官
Is something wrong?
怎麼了？
Nothing.
沒什麼
Excuse me.
告辭了
It's difficult to believe.
雖然我覺得不可能
But…
不過若是真的，那可是大事
June 21st.
6月21日
I discussed this with a colleague.
我把此事告訴了同期的同事
I heard that Akizumi was brought in to assist back then.
我聽說明墨當時有被派去支援
After some digging, things really are strange.
調查後我發現果然不太尋常
Shimizu readily confessed to the embezzlement charges,
志水明明大方承認侵占錢財的事實
but he consistently denied the murders.
卻持續否認自己有殺人
Even his detention period…
羈押時長也不對勁
totaled 65 days.
總共65天
It was extended for fabricated reasons, wasn't it?
一定是用盡各種理由延長的吧？
I'm starting to think he might have been coerced into confessing.
我猜他可能是被強迫認罪
Akizumi, do you know anything--
明墨，你知不知道什麼內情？
Any evidence?
證據呢？
Evidence that Mr. Datehara covered it up.
就是伊達原先生湮滅證據的證明
I don't--
這個嘛…
If it's just rumors, it's not worth verifying.
如果只是傳聞，沒必要查證
As a prosecutor, you should have better things to do.
你同為檢察官 應該有其他該做的事吧？
We already have enough criminals to deal with.
罪犯原本就已經多到不行了
I later learned
我後來聽說
that it was Akizumi who coerced Mr. Shimizu into confessing.
當時讓志水先生認罪的就是明墨
It was a mistake to seek his advice.
我不該找他商量的
September 6th.
9月6日
I met Detective Fukazawa.
我跟深澤刑警見了面
It seems that rumors about Mr. Datehara were started because of what he let slip.
伊達原先生的謠言 就是因為他透露的消息才傳開的
A woman came to us because she was harassed
有位持續收到偷拍影片
by someone who sent her a secretly taken video.
遭受他人騷擾的女性找我商量
When she showed it to me…
她給我看了影片後…
-You saw Mr. Shimizu in it. -Yes.
有拍到志水先生？
He admitted that the video really existed.
他確實承認該影片曾經存在
So, I reported it to Mr. Kurata, who was the chief of investigations on this case.
我向當時擔任該案件 搜查本部長的倉田先生報告
What did Mr. Kurata say?
倉田先生怎麼說？
He said he wanted to examine it carefully and asked me to hand it over.
他說想仔細確認，要我把影片交給他
So, I did.
我就照做了
Later, I was informed that the man in the video wasn't Shimizu.
後來他跟我說影片中那個人不是志水
But looking back…
但現在回想起來…
Could you testify to this?
你願意提供證詞嗎？
No, of course not.
不，你饒了我吧
And keep what I've just told you to yourself as well.
剛才講的也請你保密
If you'll excuse me.
那我走了
Mr. Fukazawa!
深澤先生！
Mr. Shimizu was definitely wrongly accused.
志水先生一定是被冤枉的
This is a big step forward.
這是很大的進展
-Could you please ask him again? -October 26th.
-10月26日… -能請你再跟本人確認一次嗎？
Mr. Shimizu still refuses to meet with me.
志水先生仍拒絕與我見面
I hope he reads my letter.
希望他有看我寄的信
March 12th.
3月12日
I learned that Mr. Shimizu's daughter has been frequenting this dog shelter.
我得知志水先生的女兒 會前往流浪狗的收容設施
You're Saya, right?
你是紗耶對吧？
Saya Makino.
牧野紗耶
I hope to gradually grow closer to her.
如果能漸漸縮短跟她的距離就好了
May 8th.
5月8日
Cocoa, Saya's dog, finally warmed up to me!
紗耶的愛犬可可終於肯親近我了
Saya is starting to smile more around me.
紗耶也開始願意對我展露笑容
Get ready, everyone!
各位，我要拍了喔！
Ms. Momose, hurry!
桃瀨小姐，快點過來…
Right.
好
Oh, it worked.
有聽到聲音
October 2nd.
10月2日
I was transferred to the Utsunomiya office.
上頭將我調派至宇都宮地檢署
It's uncommon for transfers to occur at this time of year.
通常不可能會在這種時候調動
Perhaps this is evidence that I'm getting closer to the truth.
不過這也許是 我離真相更進一步的證據
March 27th.
3月27日
I'm swamped with work.
工作多到做不完
I wish I could go to Chiba on the weekend at least
至少想在週末前往千葉
to continue investigating the case.
繼續調查案件
I don't feel very well.
最近我的身體狀況不太好
It might be fatigue.
是不是累了呢？
April 7th.
4月7日
I was diagnosed with an illness.
我被診斷出患有疾病
I feel helpless.
真是沒出息
I don't have time to be hospitalized.
現在可沒空住院啊
September 16th.
9月16日
Hospitalized again.
我再次住院
Time is running out.
我時日無多
I called Akizumi.
於是把明墨找來了
This…
這給你
is for you, Akizumi.
明墨
ITOI FAMILY MURDERS CASE
（糸井家滅門案）
You were still investigating it?
你還在調查？
Yeah.
對
You're already busy,
你原本就已經夠忙了
yet you traveled between Tochigi and Chiba.
卻在栃木跟千葉兩邊跑
And you neglected your regular checkups.
也不接受定期健康檢查
You want to say I was foolish, right?
你想罵我是笨蛋吧？
Well, you're right.
我就是個笨蛋
Now, look what's happened to me.
所以才會變成現在這樣
Mr. Shimizu was definitely falsely accused.
志水先生一定是冤案受害者
If you read the file, you'll see.
只要看過資料你就會明白
Akizumi…
明墨
You bear responsibility for coercing Mr. Shimizu into confessing.
你得為強迫志水先生認罪而負責
Just once…
一次就好
please review the file.
拜託你看一下吧
To Akizumi.
明墨收
Save Mr. Shimizu.
拯救志水先生吧
Now that I'm in this condition, I understand.
身處我如今的狀態就會明白
Life is limited
生命既有限
and precious.
而且可貴
I wish…
我也…
I could have lived longer.
想再活更久一點
But…
但是…
there's a life that can still be saved.
還有能夠拯救的生命
I wish that no one's life
希望沒有任何人
is taken away due to false accusations.
會因為自己沒犯下的罪而被剝奪性命
Their lives should never be taken
奪取生命的
because of the arrogance of the justice authorities.
絕不該是司法權力的傲慢
I strongly believe this…
這是身為檢察官的我
as one prosecutor.
殷切的期望
It is…
希望…
my sincere hope…
可以將我們
that we can restore trust and pride in the justice system.
對司法的信賴跟自豪
I wanted to see this future
我好想親眼看看
with my own eyes too.
那樣的未來啊
Alongside Akizumi.
多想跟明墨共同見證
Me too…
我也是
Momose.
桃瀨
Here.
這給你
It's from Ms. Momose's mother.
是桃瀨的母親給我的
I've gone through it all,
我全部看完了
but I didn't find any clues beyond what was already in the file.
但沒有文件內容之外的線索
I see.
是喔
I'm sure Momose must be grateful for your efforts.
你們如此竭盡心思 桃瀨一定心懷感激
Right.
希望如此
"Similar?"
“很相似？”
It must've fallen out of one of the books.
應該是原本黏在書上，後來掉下來的
SIMILAR?
（很相似？）
Aren't you going in?
你不進去嗎？
Well, even if you did, you'd probably only be met with cold stares.
不過現在的你，即使過去
Right now, anyway.
也只會被他們冷眼相待吧
I heard you're staying silent during your impeachment trial.
聽說你在彈劾審判持續保持緘默
I think you'd feel better if you opened up…
我是覺得說出來會輕鬆許多
about Datehara being the one who led you down the path of corruption.
坦承你做出違法行為的起因是伊達原
Spoken like a former prosecutor.
不愧是前檢察官
Are you planning to interrogate me?
你這是想訊問我嗎？
No, I'm not.
我並無此意
I've come to make a request.
我是來拜託你的
Won't you reveal everything at the trial?
能夠請你在法庭中 將一切全盤托出嗎？
When you delivered that verdict,
做出那判決時
you didn't know anything.
你毫不知情
You trusted the evidence presented by the prosecution.
相信檢方提出的證據
And after careful consideration,
仔細考量後
you decided that Mr. Shimizu deserved the death sentence.
你認為應當判處志水先生死刑
You only learned about the possibility of him being falsely accused
之所以會知道有冤罪的可能性
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
There was a video that proved Mr. Yusaku Shimizu's alibi.
曾有一部能證明 志水裕策先生不在場的影片
But Prosecutor Datehara covered it up.
不過已經被伊達原檢座湮滅了
Impossible.
不可能
Mr. Shimizu…
志水先生…
is innocent.
是無罪的
You were clearly shaken.
你的內心明顯產生了動搖
That's what was noted in Momose's records.
桃瀨的紀錄中是這麼寫的
You realized your error
你察覺到自己的失誤，一直很懊悔
That's why you've been donating and volunteering at the children's home
所以你才會持續 向志水紗耶所在的兒童養護設施
where Saya Shimizu lives.
不斷捐款、當志工
To at least do something to make amends.
就是為了盡可能贖罪
But that's like putting a bandage on a fatal wound.
但那種行為就像是 在致命傷口上貼OK繃
If you continue to ignore this wound,
正因為你不正視那道傷口
it can cost a life.
有個人可能會因此喪命
Before it's too late,
在事態變得無法挽回前
won't you speak out?
把真相說出來吧
It's useless.
沒用的
I don't know anything.
我什麼都不知道
Datehara…
伊達原這個人
He never tolerates anyone who strays from his rules.
絕對不會原諒 有人不遵守他訂立的規則
You'll be crushed soon too.
你也很快就會被擊潰
I don't care.
我沒差
When you have nothing to lose, you can do anything.
若沒什麼好失去的，就等於是無敵的
Am I wrong,
我有說錯嗎？
Judge Seko?
瀨古判事
I'm home.
我回來了
Hey.
回來啦
Seriously, Yuna!
真是的，結奈！
Welcome back.
回來了啊
What happened?
怎麼了嗎？
She said she'd study, but she was secretly watching videos again.
那孩子說要讀書 卻又偷偷躲起來看影片
What?
什麼？
What's the big deal?
又沒關係
I was among the top in the mock exams the other day.
之前的模擬考我成績也是前幾名啊
Yuna.
結奈
I know you're working hard.
我知道你有在努力
But…
但是呢
it's not okay to break the rules.
違反規則是不對的
People who break the rules get punished.
違規者會被懲罰
And it's your father's job to administer these punishments.
對他們進行懲處就是爸爸的工作
Forget it.
別再說了
Yuna…
看來對結奈…
Do I need to punish you too?
也得給予懲罰才行是嗎？
Fine. I'm sorry.
知道了啦，對不起
Good girl.
乖孩子
Check these out.
請看看這些
Here are the weeklies issued today.
是今天開賣的週刊
What the…
這是…
Datehara is manipulating information through the media.
伊達原開始對媒體 進行印象管理的操作了吧
"Attorney Akizumi has successfully secured many acquittals for the accused."
“在多起案件中 讓嫌疑人獲判無罪的明墨律師
"But he has been unmasked."
被摘下了面具
"In defending Mr. Keita Hiyama, who faces a second instance for murder,
他在殺人案二審中擔任上訴人 緋山啓太先生的辯護律師
it is whispered that Akizumi
疑似違法藏匿證據，試圖抹滅犯罪”
This one mentions Mr. Shimizu's case.
這裡有提到志水先生的案件
"Regarding his claims that Shimizu was falsely accused,
“他主張志水死刑犯是被冤枉的
they lack sufficient evidence."
卻缺乏證據
"Attorney Akizumi has been in contact with Shimizu's daughter."
明墨律師跟志水死刑犯的女兒有往來
"It appears his claims may be driven by personal emotions."
看來是因為私人情感而主張冤罪”
How awful to mention Saya as well.
太差勁了
Do they think they can ruin people's lives just to boost sales?
怎麼能為了銷量隨便毀了別人的人生
The media might also go to Mr. Hiyama.
媒體可能也會去找緋山先生
Akamine.
赤峰
On it.
我明白
What about the jacket?
之前那件外套呢？
It's kept in the office.
保管在事務所中
Don't worry about it.
你不用擔心
Go ahead.
這邊請
Dad…
爸爸…
He is going to be okay, right?
不會有事吧？
Yes.
沒問題的
Then I'm fine.
那我也不要緊
I'll trust you and wait.
我會相信你，繼續等下去
We have the media's attention right now.
現在媒體也在關注
So, if Akizumi comes here, it could cause issues for Ms. Saya.
如果明墨過來 可能會給紗耶小姐造成困擾
Thank you so much…
竟如此為我們著想
for everything.
真的很謝謝你們
And for pushing for the retrial.
再審的事情也一樣
Thank you for doing your best despite the lost footage.
即使影片被奪走，卻還是這麼拼命
Right now,
我們正盡己所能 尋找能聲請再審的證據
But truthfully, it's not that easy…
但說實在的，很難做到
So, I've come today to ask you something.
因此我今天來是有求於你
Could you please recount
能再跟我說一次
what happened back then once more, in detail?
當時的情況嗎？
I understand it may be painful for you to remember.
雖然對志水先生來說 回想起來肯定會很痛苦
But…
但是…
any trivial information will help.
不管是多細微的情報都好
Please.
拜託你了
Actually…
其實…
Please handle this.
麻煩你了
All right.
好的
How did it go?
情況如何？
No luck again today.
今天也沒見到
I see.
這樣啊
What's that?
那是什麼？
Mr. Shimizu lent it to me.
志水先生借給我的
It contains his notes from back then.
是事件當時寫的嫌犯筆記
Did you find any clues?
有找到什麼線索嗎？
No.
沒有
It's just that…
只覺得…
going through it is quite painful.
要看下去會很不好受
May I?
能借我看嗎？
Sure.
當然好
Five days since my arrest.
被逮捕後的第5天…
You did it, didn't you?
是你幹的吧？
I was interrogated about my alibi.
警方就不在場證明進行了訊問
Please let me go.
請讓我回家
Despite my denials,
即使拒絕，也被關著長達10小時
Ten days since my arrest.
被逮捕後的第10天
I was interrogated about the circumstances of the crime.
警方對犯罪當時的情況 進行偵訊並做筆錄
The interrogation went on for 11 hours.
過程長達11小時
No food or drink provided.
對方沒有提供食物跟水
Your daughter is still--
你女兒還…
As I said, I was--
所以說我真的沒有…
Vomiting, diarrhea,
嘔吐、腹瀉 眼瞼下垂跟無力肢體麻痺
These symptoms were already showing when you left, right?
這些症狀在你離開前就出現了吧？
Did you enjoy seeing them?
你看得很開心嗎？
How could I enjoy…
那麼殘忍的事情
such a cruel sight?!
我怎麼可能做得到！
I have a daughter too!
我也是有女兒的！
Haven't you had enough?
已經夠了吧？
Let me out of here!
讓我離開！
Let me see Saya!
我要見紗耶！
Please!
拜託了！
Please let me out!
算我求你，讓我出去！
Twenty-five days since my arrest.
被逮捕後第25天
I was interrogated about the circumstances of the crime.
警方對犯案當時的詳情進行訊問調查
The interrogation went on for 11 hours.
訊問時間11小時
No food or drink provided.
沒有提供食物跟水
Listen.
聽著
We'll write down that you confessed.
我們就寫說你認罪了喔
No.
不是我做的
I've lost even the will to respond.
我甚至沒力氣回答
What can I possibly say to someone who won't listen?
對不願意聽的人，還有什麼好說的？
Fifty-two days since my arrest.
被逮捕後的第52天…
How do you think your daughter will continue living?
你覺得你女兒接下來要怎麼活下去？
"The daughter of a murderer."
殺人犯的女兒
She'll have no choice but to live hiding that fact.
她只能隱藏此身分過活
Is Saya the daughter of a murderer?
紗耶是殺人犯的女兒嗎？
You've embezzled funds
侵占錢財
and killed people.
殺人
And you continue to lie.
還一直說謊
I wonder what your daughter will think of such a father.
有這種父親，女兒會有何感想？
I want to see Saya.
我好想見紗耶
I heard about your wife.
我聽說你太太的事情了
It was a traffic accident.
她遇上交通事故啊
Your daughter…
你女兒…
has been taken in by a children's home.
由兒童養護設施接手照顧
I want to see Saya.
我好想見紗耶
I want to see her.
我想見她
I WANT TO SEE SAYA
（我好想見紗耶）
It leaves you…
講不出…
speechless.
任何話吧？
Mr. Akizumi has been carrying the regret all this time.
明墨律師一直背負著當時的後悔
Is something the matter?
怎麼了嗎？
The detective mentioned ptosis and flaccid paralysis.
刑警說的話
What about it?
有疑點嗎？
I'm currently handling a mass food poisoning case
我正在處理集體食物中毒案
and researching various poisons.
所以查了很多關於毒物的資訊
I don't think thallium could cause such…
鉈會導致那種症狀嗎？
Just as I thought!
果然是這樣！
Vomiting, stomach pain, diarrhea, and other digestive symptoms.
“嘔吐、腹痛、腹瀉 消化管出血等消化器官症狀
Additionally, neurological symptoms
而神經系統的症狀
such as somnolence, coma, convulsions, blindness, and facial nerve paralysis.
則有嗜睡、昏睡、痙攣發作 失明、顏面神經麻痺”
Nowhere does it mention ptosis…
“眼瞼下垂跟無力肢體麻痺”
and flaccid paralysis.
完全沒有寫到
Those terms are absent from the prosecution's report too.
檢方的調查書裡也沒有記述
What could this mean?
你覺得這是怎麼回事？
Either the detective made a mistake or…
可能是刑警搞錯
Mr. Shimizu remembered it incorrectly.
或是志水先生記錯
Or…
不然就是…
Maybe…
該不會…
Every discovery and invention in the world…
這世上的任何發現或發明…
…are built on speculation and theories.
-都是以推測與假說為基礎並成立的
According to the prosecution's report,
根據檢方調查書
the drug and poison test was carried out at the Chiba Police crime lab.
進行毒藥物鑑定的是千葉縣警科搜研
The test results indicated that the poison used was thallium.
從鑑定結果得知使用的毒物為鉈
Mr. Shimizu could have obtained this from the company's warehouse.
這可能是志水先生從公司倉庫拿走的
What about it?
有什麼問題嗎？
The detective who questioned Mr. Shimizu on the 10th day of his arrest stated this.
他被逮捕的十天後 負責訊問的刑警這麼說
"The Itoi family showed
糸井一家出現了
symptoms of vomiting, diarrhea, ptosis, and flaccid paralysis."
“嘔吐、腹瀉 眼瞼下垂跟無力肢體麻痺的症狀”
However, thallium does not cause symptoms such as ptosis and flaccid paralysis.
然而鉈並不會出現 眼瞼下垂跟無力肢體麻痺的症狀
By the time of the interrogation,
在警方進行訊問時
So, why did the detective mention these symptoms?
為什麼刑警會這麼說呢？
It's possible it was just a mistake.
雖然也可能單純是搞錯
But terms like ptosis and flaccid paralysis
但是“眼瞼下垂跟無力肢體麻痺”
are not commonly used unless referenced from specific documents.
如果不是邊看資料邊唸 平常很少會用到這種詞彙
What if this wasn't merely a mistake?
如果這不是弄錯…
Perhaps someone intentionally altered the poison test results.
就是某人故意竄改了毒物鑑定結果
Yes.
沒錯
Testing poisons is complex and identifying them takes time.
毒物鑑定相當困難 要找出明確毒物很花時間
Thallium sulfate, easily accessible to Mr. Shimizu,
硫酸亞鉈是志水先生容易取得的毒
would've been compelling material for his indictment.
為了起訴，是很有說服力的說法
Mr. Akizumi, you were called in from the Saitama office
你從埼玉地檢署趕來支援時
during the final period of Mr. Shimizu's detention.
志水先生的羈押期間已接近尾聲
By then, the results had already been altered,
鑑定結果這時早已被竄改 根本沒人會去懷疑
This is just the story we--
以上這些內容是我們的推測
If I were to add to your story, it would go like this.
若用那套說法進一步推測 事情經過如下
Datehara was feeling frustrated.
伊達原當時非常焦躁
Despite having Mr. Shimizu in detention,
雖然已將志水先生羈押
there wasn't enough evidence to indict him.
卻沒有足以起訴的證據
…such a cruel sight?!
我怎麼可能做得到！
At this rate, he risked losing Shimizu due to insufficient evidence.
這樣下去，會因為證據不足 讓志水逃過一劫
Let me see Saya!
我要見紗耶！
This would set him back in uncovering
那樣會更難找出 西千葉建設侵占案的真相
For Datehara, this outcome was absolutely unacceptable.
對伊達原來說，那是要極力避免的
"In that case, I'll fabricate evidence that incriminates Shimizu," he thought.
既然如此，他乾脆捏造出 能證明志水是犯人的證據
With this in mind,
如此盤算的伊達原
he instructed the head of the crime lab to alter the test results
命令科搜研的負責人竄改鑑定結果
to indicate a poison that would cause symptoms similar to the one used.
改成跟拿來犯案的毒 擁有相似症狀的毒物
Similar?
“很相似？”
I see.
原來如此
SIMILAR?
（很相似？）
Momose had realized.
桃瀨發現了
I see.
這樣啊
By "similar," she meant the poison?
是指毒物很相似
There were a few books on poison, right?
我記得有幾本毒物的專門書對吧？
-Yes. -Let's pull them all out.
-對 -全都拿出來吧
Let's list everything that shows symptoms of ptosis and flaccid paralysis,
把會造成眼瞼下垂 跟無力肢體麻痺的毒物都列出來
and find one similar to thallium.
看哪一個跟鉈相似
Poliovirus.
小兒麻痺症病毒
The timing for the onset of symptoms doesn't match.
出現症狀的時間不一致
Enterovirus.
腸病毒
This also doesn't fit the situation.
也跟這次的情況不符合
Next is botulinum toxin.
再來是肉毒桿菌毒素
Botulinum toxin.
“肉毒桿菌毒素
Early symptoms include vomiting, diarrhea, and other digestive issues.
初期會有嘔吐跟腹瀉等消化器官症狀
Later symptoms include ptosis, blurred vision, difficulty swallowing…
之後則會出現眼瞼下垂 複視、吞嚥障礙
and flaccid paralysis.
也會有無力肢體麻痺的症狀”
It's similar.
非常相似
This must be it, right?
該不會就是這個吧？
This is it.
絕對沒錯
So Momose had realized.
桃瀨那時果然察覺到了
"Doctor."
“醫生”
"Tampered"?
“竄改”？
Perhaps this means…
也許…
Momose realized something after consulting with a doctor.
她在跟醫生對話時發現了什麼
I've heard from Ms. Momose's mother that even while hospitalized,
我是聽桃瀨小姐的母親說的
She discovered the possible tampering and intended to investigate it further.
桃瀨是發現竄改的可能性 打算從那裡繼續查下去吧
Mr. Aoyama, do you know who conducted the poison test?
青山先生，能夠查到 毒物鑑定人的名字嗎？
Satoshi Hiratsuka. He resigned and now lives in Nerima Ward.
他叫平塚聰 八年前離職，現在住在練馬區
I'll go talk to him right away.
我立刻去問他
Do so.
拜託你了
Also…
另外…
Ms. Shinomiya…
至於紫之宮小姐…
You've finally agreed to see us.
你終於願意會客了
I've come to say something to you.
我是有話要跟你說才來的
Stop involving my daughter!
不准再繼續牽連我女兒！
Dad!
爸爸！
Unfortunately, I have no intention of letting her go.
很可惜，我並沒有要放她走
Your daughter is still valuable to me.
你女兒對我來說還有利用價值
How dare you!
開什麼玩笑？你把我女兒當成什麼？
She's an exceptionally skilled and useful subordinate.
她是相當優秀又好用的部下
She's particularly effective at shaking you up.
特別適合用來使你動搖
I'm here today because I need to ask you something.
我們今天來，是想問你
It's about the Itoi family murders.
關於糸井家滅門案的事
I won't tell you anything.
我不打算跟你談
Is that for your daughter?
是為了你女兒嗎？
Datehara is quite ruthless, isn't he?
伊達原也真壞
He's taken your daughter as hostage.
竟拿別人的女兒當人質
If you're not careful with your words, your daughter's future could be ruined.
如果不小心說了什麼 女兒的未來就會被摧毀
You may not care if you're arrested,
自己被抓沒關係
but you'll protect your daughter.
但要保護女兒
What a beautiful display of paternal love.
這父愛可真美好啊
What does that mean?
這是怎麼回事？
So you've kept silent all this time…
你過去之所以一直閉口不談
for my sake?
是為了我？
Just go already.
你們回去吧
Give me a break!
別開玩笑了！
So what about my future?
我的將來算什麼？
I couldn't care less about it!
那種事怎樣都沒差！
Mr. Shimizu was falsely accused and has no idea when he'll be executed!
志水先生可是蒙受冤罪 不知道什麼時候會被處死
What future could possibly outweigh someone's life?
怎麼會有比人命還重要的將來？
And you realize, don't you?
而且你應該知道吧？
That if Mr. Shimizu didn't do it, the real culprit is still out there!
志水先生不是犯人 真正的犯人還在外面逍遙
And yet…
但爸爸你…
you've turned a blind eye for years.
卻幾年來都假裝視而不見
How can you…
你那樣…
call yourself a police officer?
你那樣還算是警察嗎？
In Mr. Shimizu's notebook…
這是志水先生的筆記本
the latter half is all about Saya.
後半全都在寫紗耶的事
"I want to see her."
“好想見她…”
I WANT TO SEE HER
（好想見她）
Can you even imagine…
你認為志水先生 是抱著什麼樣的心情？
I WANT TO SEE SAYA BEFORE I DIE
（我想在死前見紗耶一面）
…how Mr. Shimizu must have felt?
你能想像嗎？爸爸
Come on.
說話啊
Answer me, Dad!
回答我，爸爸！
I have imagined it.
我想像過啊
Countless times.
非常多次
Over and over!
我想像了無數次
When I saw that footage,
當我看到那部影片
honestly, I thought I should make it public immediately.
老實說，我認為應該要立刻公開
But…
然而…
By then…
在那時候
Shimizu's trial had already started.
志水的審判已經開始了
I'll only say this once.
這些話我只會說一次
The police…
警方並沒有發現這部影片
-But… -No buts!
-但是… -不准頂嘴！
You're telling me now that he's innocent?
事到如今說他無罪？
Imagine making this public!
這種事情怎麼能被公開！
This won't just be your responsibility or mine!
這可不是我們兩個負責 就能解決的事！
Resigning and abandoning our duties is out of the question!
當然也不可以辭職逃避責任！
That won't absolve us in any way!
那樣做完全無法償還罪孽！
Shimizu's family has been torn apart,
志水家已經崩壞了
and his wife has passed away.
妻子也過世了
The media will accuse us of causing her death,
媒體會吵著說是我們殺的人
saying, "They deserve the same fate." "Murderers."
說我們應該遭受同等待遇，是殺人犯
The public's harsh scrutiny will mercilessly fall on our families!
來自社會的批判 會毫不留情地指向我們的家人！
Even on your daughter!
你女兒也不例外！
This…
我這番話…
isn't a threat.
不是恐嚇
I'm going to have a child soon…
我們家…
after waiting for so long!
很快會迎來好不容易懷上的孩子
I will bear…
我跟你會…
the same cross as you.
背負相同的十字架
I feel…
對志水先生…
very sorry…
我打從心底
for Mr. Shimizu.
感到抱歉
But now…
但是…
it can't…
我已經…
be undone.
無法挽回了
"You murderer!"
殺人凶手！
To escape that accusation…
為了不被冠上那樣的名號
you're going to let a person die, is that it?
你正打算對人見死不救
As you've said,
你說的沒錯
even if you regret it now, the past can never be undone.
現在再怎麼後悔也無法回到過去
But the future is different.
但未來不一樣
You can still save Mr. Shimizu's life.
你現在還能拯救志水先生的命
Tell me, Mr. Kurata.
回答我，倉田先生
The poison used in the Itoi family murders,
糸井家滅門案中使用的毒
it wasn't really thallium sulfate, was it?
其實不是硫酸亞鉈吧？
The poison test results were altered!
毒物鑑定的結果被竄改過了
Dad…
爸爸
It's possible.
的確…
Early in the investigation,
在搜查初期
there was confusion regarding the poison.
關於毒物的資訊非常混亂
But then, someone from the crime lab came with a report.
但有次科搜研的人前來報告
He said that thallium sulfate was detected on the table,
說從桌上驗出的毒物是硫酸亞鉈
and the same substance was found on the bodies.
而且從遺體上也驗出了相同毒物
I understand identifying poisons is tricky.
我聽說毒物鑑定很困難
It often requires a great amount of time.
經常需要花上不少時間
So…
所以…
I didn't think it was particularly unusual.
我當時不覺得有什麼奇怪的
Can you confirm that the person from the crime lab…
你說的那名科搜研人員
was Satoshi Hiratsuka?
是平塚聰，對嗎？
I can.
沒錯
But…
只不過…
I see.
這樣啊
Yes.
是的
He passed away three years ago due to illness.
他的確在三年前因病過世
Find Hiratsuka's former assistant.
幫我找出曾擔任他助手的人
Right.
我明白了
I've made a list of people who were Hiratsuka's assistants.
我正把曾擔任平塚助手的人列成清單
I think I can meet with some of them this week.
這週應該就能跟其中幾位碰面
Akamine…
赤峰
thank you for your help.
謝謝你在各方面的幫忙
I hope we can uncover even a small clue.
如果能找到一些線索就好了
Hey!
等等
What's this about?
有什麼事？
We're the police.
我們是警察
Is Mr. Masaki Akizumi here?
明墨正樹先生在嗎？
Why do you want him?
你們找他做什麼？
-Hey. -Hey, hold on!
-站住 -等一下
-Hey! -You can't!
-等等！ -這樣我們很困擾！
-Wait! -Hey!
-請等一下！ -停下來！
It's the police.
我們是警察
Are you Mr. Masaki Akizumi?
你是明墨正樹先生吧？
We have an arrest warrant for you
因為你在羽木精工社長殺人案中
for covering up evidence in the murder of Hanegi Seiko's president.
犯了湮滅證據罪，我們有你的逮捕令
Come on, stand up.
給我站起來！
Arrest?
逮捕？
Let's go.
我們走
Begin searching.
開始找證物吧
-Right.
-遵命
-Come in. -Excuse me.
-請進 -打擾了
It appears Akizumi was arrested earlier.
明墨剛才似乎被警方拘留了
Was he now?
這樣啊
Poor guy.
還真是可憐
Do you think so?
會嗎？
I think it's only what he deserves.
我倒覺得他是罪有應得
But are you sure?
但這樣真的好嗎？
You were somewhat in his debt, weren't you?
明墨對你有恩吧？
HIYAMA
（緋山）
Not really.
並沒有
After a skilled attorney joined, he didn't need me anymore.
有位優秀的律師來了 所以我沒了利用價值
Should I work on Akizumi's trial?
明墨的官司可以由我負責嗎？
No.
不
I'll handle it.
由我來吧
For Akizumi's sake as well,
得替明墨著想
let's put an end to this.
這也是為了對方 就讓我們來結束一切吧
Mr. Akizumi!
明墨律師！
I'll leave the rest to you.
剩下的就交給你們了
I've dreamed of seeing you like this for a long time.
我從很久以前就在想像 你會變成這副模樣
How could he conceal evidence of murder?
太不合理了，竟隱匿殺人的證據
I killed him.
人是我殺的
He must have left something.
律師可能有留下什麼
I have something to say.
我有話想跟你說
A precious life is at stake.
這攸關寶貴的生命！
I couldn't believe her.
我當時沒能相信他
-Shimizu is a criminal! -Objection!
-志水可是罪犯！ -我有異議！
There's something only I can do.
有些事只有我做得到
We will bear the responsibility.
我們會負起責任
People compete and take from each other. That's just how the world works.
互相競爭並搶奪
Together, let's go to hell.
我們一起下地獄吧